You look so much like your mother Lingwu,
أنت تشبه والدتك كثيرًا لينغ وو،
almost identical.
متطابقة تقريبا.
Well,
حسنًا،
do you know who killed my parents?
هل تعرف من قتل والدي؟
I only remember
انا فقط أتذكر
that your parents died on the young master's 18th birthday.
أن والديك ماتا في عيد ميلاد الشاب الثامن عشر.
Today is my beloved son Silin's birthday.
اليوم هو عيد ميلاد ابني الحبيب سيلين.
Thank you all for coming.
شكرا لكم جميعا على حضوركم.
Have a drink.
تناول مشروب.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
That day, Mrs. Liu gave your mother a wooden box.
في ذلك اليوم، أعطت السيدة ليو والدتك صندوقًا خشبيًا.
A wooden box?
صندوق خشبي؟
What kind of wooden box was it?
ما نوع الصندوق الخشبي الذي كان؟
I vaguely remember that wooden box was special.
أتذكر بشكل غامض أن هذا الصندوق الخشبي كان مميزًا.
There was an evening primrose carved on the lid.
كان هناك زهرة الربيع المسائية محفورة على الغطاء.
Evening primrose?
زهرة الربيع المسائية؟
That day...
ذلك اليوم...
We were extremely busy.
لقد كنا مشغولين للغاية.
The master was preparing for the young master's birthday.
كان المعلم يستعد لعيد ميلاد المعلم الشاب.
It was quite hectic.
لقد كان مرهقًا جدًا.
Many distinguished guests came.
حضر العديد من الضيوف المميزين.
We didn't hear about your parents until that evening.
لم نسمع عن والديك حتى ذلك المساء.
Did anything else happen that day?
هل حدث أي شيء آخر في ذلك اليوم؟
Oh, right.
أوه، صحيح.
I remember a young maid named Xiuhe also had an incident.
أتذكر أن خادمة شابة تدعى Xiuhe تعرضت أيضًا لحادث.
Xiuhe?
شيوهي؟
She was found dead in a pond.
تم العثور عليها ميتة في بركة.
It was discovered right around the same time as your parents' incident.
لقد تم اكتشافه في نفس الوقت تقريبًا الذي حدث فيه حادث والديك.
When they found her, her body was pale from the water.
عندما وجدوها، كان جسدها شاحبًا بسبب الماء.
There was also a bullet hole in her head.
وكان هناك أيضًا ثقب رصاصة في رأسها.
Who knows who she offended.
من يعلم من أساءت إليه؟
So young.
صغير جدا.
Such a pity.
من المؤسف حقا.
I don't know if she had any family left.
لا أعلم إذا كان لديها أي عائلة متبقية.
Zixin.
زيكسين.
Ah!
اه!
Are you alright?
هل انت بخير؟
Ah, I'm fine.
اه، أنا بخير.
I remember when you first came to the Liu residence, you called me Xiuhe.
أتذكر عندما أتيت لأول مرة إلى مقر إقامة ليو، كنت تناديني بـ Xiuhe.
Could it be that you knew her?
هل من الممكن أنك عرفتها؟
To be honest with you.
لأكون صادقا معك.
Actually, Xiuhe
في الواقع، شيو هي
is my cousin.
هو ابن عمي.
She's your cousin?
هل هي ابنة عمك؟
So you came to the Liu residence to find the real culprit.
لقد أتيت إلى منزل ليو للعثور على الجاني الحقيقي.
That's right.
هذا صحيح.
Zixin.
زيكسين.
Don't be sad.
لا تحزن.
The dead cannot come back to life.
الموتى لا يستطيعون العودة إلى الحياة.
But I believe one day the murderer will be brought to justice.
لكنني أعتقد أن القاتل سوف يُقدم إلى العدالة يومًا ما.
Yiyu.
ممكن.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
I...
أنا...
I'll go now. Be careful.
سأذهب الآن. كن حذرًا.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
You've already forgotten the slap
لقد نسيت الصفعة بالفعل
you owe me so soon?
هل أنت مدين لي بهذه السرعة؟
You really have thick skin.
لديك حقا جلد سميك.
My hand hurt from slapping you.
يدي تؤلمني من صفعتك.
You do have some charm,
لديك بعض السحر
but you're nothing but common trash.
لكنك لست سوى قمامة عادية.
How dare you compare yourself to me?
كيف تجرؤ على مقارنة نفسك بي؟
If I killed you,
إذا قتلتك
certain people would be heartbroken.
بعض الناس سوف يشعرون بالحزن.
I'll give you a cold shower instead,
سأعطيك دشًا باردًا بدلاً من ذلك،
to help you come to your senses
لمساعدتك على العودة إلى رشدك
and see your true worth.
وانظر إلى قيمتك الحقيقية.
Pour!
ل!
Look at you, like a drowned rat
أنظر إليك، مثل فأر غارق
and still acting proud in front of me.
ومازال يتصرف بفخر أمامي.
Sinan.
سنان.
Sinan, don't go.
سنان لا تذهب.
How long have I been asleep?
كم من الوقت كنت نائما؟
Three days and nights.
ثلاثة أيام وليالي.
Eat this.
أكل هذا.
You've been taking care of me all this time?
لقد كنت تعتني بي طوال هذا الوقت؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
I'm the one who brought you back after all.
أنا من أعادك بعد كل شيء.
You must be hungry.
لابد أنك جائع.
Open your mouth.
افتح فمك
Is it good?
هل هو جيد؟
Commander Xu,
القائد شو،
I'm truly grateful to you this time.
أنا ممتن لك حقا هذه المرة.
Without your help,
بدون مساعدتك،
this shipment would never have made it into Yun City.
هذه الشحنة لم تكن لتصل إلى مدينة يون أبدًا.
Here,
هنا،
let me toast to both of you.
دعوني أرفع نخبًا لكليكما.
Second Master.
المعلم الثاني.
Come.
يأتي.
Mr. Sun, you're being too polite.
السيد صن، أنت مهذب للغاية.
I, Commander Xu, should be the one thanking you.
أنا، القائد شو، يجب أن أكون الشخص الذي يشكرك.
Everyone thinks being a commander is so impressive,
يعتقد الجميع أن كونك قائدًا أمر مثير للإعجاب،
with hundreds of men and guns under my command.
مع مئات الرجال والبنادق تحت قيادتي.
But who knows that I have so many mouths to feed,
ولكن من يدري أن لدي الكثير من الأفواه التي يجب أن أطعمها،
and horses to feed too?
والخيول لتغذيتها أيضًا؟
Yes, indeed.
نعم بالفعل.
Every day I wake up to nothing but expenses.
كل يوم أستيقظ ولا أجد شيئًا سوى النفقات.
You've really saved me from a desperate situation.
لقد أنقذتني حقا من موقف يائس.
Not at all.
مُطْلَقاً.
Exactly.
بالضبط.
I really must thank young Sinan.
يجب علي حقًا أن أشكر الشاب سنان.
If not for his intelligence and capability,
إن لم يكن لذكائه وقدرته،
we wouldn't have had this opportunity to cooperate.
لم تكن لدينا هذه الفرصة للتعاون.
The Commander is absolutely right.
القائد على حق تماما.
You've found yourself an excellent son-in-law.
لقد وجدت لنفسك صهرًا ممتازًا.
Sinan is a talented young man, not to be underestimated.
سنان شاب موهوب، لا ينبغي الاستهانة به.
Second Master, you're too kind.
سيدي الثاني، أنت لطيف جدًا.
In business,
في مجال الأعمال،
I still have much to learn from you.
لا زال لدي الكثير لأتعلمه منك.
Come, Second Master, let's drink up.
تعال يا سيدي الثاني، دعنا نشرب.
Good.
جيد.
To you.
لك.
What a good drinker!
يا له من شارب جيد!
By the way, Commander, Sinan,
بالمناسبة يا قائد سنان
here's your share of the profits.
وهنا نصيبك من الأرباح.
Commander, Sinan, rest assured,
يا قائد سنان، اطمئن،
next time it will be even more.
المرة القادمة ستكون أكثر من ذلك.
Sinan.
سنان.
You're much more open-minded than that stubborn father of yours.
أنت أكثر انفتاحًا من والدك العنيد.
We're in business.
نحن في العمل.
We do whatever makes money.
نحن نفعل كل ما يجلب المال.
Why bother with so many rules?
لماذا نهتم بالعديد من القواعد؟
Your father is just too stubborn and rigid.
والدك عنيد جدًا ومتشدد.
That's why...
لهذا السبب...
I prefer working with people like the Second Young Master.
أفضّل العمل مع أشخاص مثل الشاب الثاني.
He's got brains. Come, come.
إنه لديه عقل. تعال، تعال.
Let's have another drink.
دعونا نتناول مشروبًا آخر.
Come, come.
تعال، تعال.
Madam.
سيدتي.
Someone outside the mansion asked me to give you this letter.
لقد طلب مني شخص خارج القصر أن أعطيك هذه الرسالة.
Yiyu.
ممكن.
Master Zhang died of a sudden heart attack last night.
توفي المعلم تشانغ بسبب نوبة قلبية مفاجئة الليلة الماضية.
I've asked the neighbors around.
لقد سألت الجيران حول.
Master Zhang never had such symptoms before.
لم يعاني السيد تشانغ من مثل هذه الأعراض من قبل.
I think something fishy is going on.
أعتقد أن هناك شيئًا مريبًا يحدث.
Madam.
سيدتي.
It's going to snow.
سوف يتساقط الثلج.
I'd like to sit here for a while.
أريد الجلوس هنا لبعض الوقت.
Yiyu.
ممكن.
Yiyu, you're here.
ييو، أنت هنا.
I've been looking all over for you.
لقد كنت أبحث عنك في كل مكان.
Young Master, what brings you here?
سيدي الشاب، ما الذي أتى بك إلى هنا؟
Today is your birthday.
اليوم عيد ميلادك .
I came to bring you a birthday gift.
لقد جئت لأحضر لك هدية عيد ميلاد.
What's wrong with you?
ما مشكلتك؟
The First Young Mistress caught a cold a few days ago.
لقد أصيبت السيدة الشابة الأولى بنزلة برد منذ بضعة أيام.
She was unconscious for several days and nights.
لقد كانت فاقدة للوعي لعدة أيام وليالي.
She's only just started to recover today.
لقد بدأت للتو في التعافي اليوم.
Yiyu, what happened to you?
يييو ماذا حدث لك؟
How could you be so careless?
كيف يمكنك أن تكون مهملاً إلى هذا الحد؟
Caiyue.
كايو.
You may leave now.
يمكنك المغادرة الآن.
What does the Second Young Master want with me?
ماذا يريد الشاب الثاني مني؟
I came specially to celebrate your birthday today.
لقد جئت خصيصا للاحتفال بعيد ميلادك اليوم.
I might have forgotten if you hadn't mentioned it.
ربما كنت قد نسيت لو لم تذكر ذلك.
Second Young Master, please don't trouble yourself.
السيد الشاب الثاني، من فضلك لا تزعج نفسك.
I want for nothing in the Liu family.
لا أريد أي شيء في عائلة ليو.
Why don't you give it to your Miss Xu instead?
لماذا لا تعطيها لسيدتك شو بدلا من ذلك؟
Yiyu.
ممكن.
I've already explained to you.
لقد شرحت لك بالفعل.
You're the only one in my heart.
أنت الوحيد في قلبي.
Why are you being so petty?
لماذا أنت حقير هكذا؟
I'm being petty?
هل أنا تافه؟
Do you know what she did?
هل تعلم ماذا فعلت؟
Her? What could she possibly do?
هي؟ ماذا يمكنها أن تفعل؟
She just shops and buys clothes all day.
إنها فقط تتسوق وتشتري الملابس طوال اليوم.
Or sits at home doing nothing.
أو يجلس في المنزل ولا يفعل شيئًا.
It seems you really don't know her at all.
يبدو أنك لا تعرفها على الإطلاق.
What's there to know about a spoiled daddy's girl?
ماذا يجب أن تعرف عن ابنة أبيها المدلل؟
Yiyu.
ممكن.
Don't stoop to her level.
لا تنحدر إلى مستواها.
She's spoiled, willful, and immature.
إنها مدللة، متعمدة، وغير ناضجة.
You're reasonable and cultured.
أنت معقول ومثقف.
I'm reasonable?
هل انا معقول؟
So being reasonable means I deserve to be bullied?
فهل كونك معقولاً يعني أنني أستحق أن أتعرض للتنمر؟
Do you know how I got this illness?
هل تعلم كيف أصبت بهذا المرض؟
If I killed you,
إذا قتلتك
certain people would be heartbroken.
بعض الناس سوف يشعرون بالحزن.
How about a cold shower instead,
ماذا عن الاستحمام بالماء البارد بدلا من ذلك؟
to help you come to your senses
لمساعدتك على العودة إلى رشدك
and see what you're really worth.
وانظر ما تستحقه حقًا.
Yu
يو
Cheng Wenyi Li Baorong Wu Wujin Hua Hongtao Rong Long Hongxu
تشنغ وينيي لي باورونغ وو ووجين هوا هونغتاو رونغ لونغ هونغكسو
Hongtao
هونغتاو
Long Hongxu Zhi
لونغ هونغشو تشى
Wu Wujin Hua Hongtao Rong Long Hongxu Zhi Guang Yandi Bao Li Long Ming Long Kun Ji Ran Ping Xiang Shidi Tao Lei Wen Li Bin Ping Cai Chao Lei Pengchao
وو ووجين هوا هونغتاو رونغ لونغ هونغكسو تشي غوانغ ياندي باو لي لونغ مينغ لونغ كون جي ران بينغ شيانغ شيدي تاو لي ون لي بينج كاي تشاو لي بنغشاو
Long Ming Long Kun Ji Ran Ping Xiang Shidi Tao Lei Wen Li Bin Ping Cai Chao Lei Pengchao Chang Ting Yue Bo Zhang Fengchao Nan Qin Dongzhu Qun Dong Liu Jing
لونغ مينغ لونغ كون جي ران بينغ شيانغ شيدي تاو لي ون لي بن بينغ كاي تشاو لي بنغشاو تشانغ تينغ يو بو تشانغ فنغ تشاو نان تشين دونغ تشو تشون دونغ ليو جينغ
Ran Ping Xiang Shidi Tao Lei Wen Li Bin Ping Cai Chao Lei Pengchao Chang Ting Yue Bo Zhang Fengchao Nan Qin Dongzhu Qun Dong Liu Jing Hong Jun Lu
ران بينغ شيانغ شيدي تاو لي ون لي بينج كاي تشاو لي بينجتشاو تشانغ تينغ يو بو تشانغ فنغ تشاو نان تشين دونغتشو تشون دونغ ليو جينغ هونغ جون لو
Yang Shidi Tao Lei Wen Li Bin Ping Cai Chao Lei Pengchao Chang Ting Yue Bo Zhang Fengchao Nan Qin Dongzhu Qun Dong Liu Jing Hong
يانغ شيدي تاو لي ون لي بن بينغ كاي تشاو لي بينجتشاو تشانغ تينغ يو بو تشانغ فنغ تشاو نان تشين دونغ تشو تشون دونغ ليو جينغ هونغ
Bo Zhang Fengchao
بو تشانغ فينغشاو
Lei Pengchao Chang Ting Yue Bo Zhang Fengchao Nan Qin Dongzhu Qun Dong Liu Jing Hong Jun Lu Ling Tuan Gang Hong Dong Bin You Ping Gang Qiu Liang Jun
لي بنغ تشاو تشانغ تينغ يو بو تشانغ فنغ تشاو نان تشين دونغ تشو تشون دونغ ليو جينغ هونغ يونيو لو لينغ توان قانغ هونغ دونغ بن يو بينغ قانغ تشيو ليانغ يونيو
Bo Zhang Fengchao Nan Qin Dongzhu Qun Dong Liu Jing Hong Jun Lu Ling Tuan Gang Hong Dong Bin You Ping Gang Qiu Liang Jun Qian Fa Shan Kai Yue Qiu Wei Shuo
بو تشانغ فنغ تشاو نان تشين دونغ تشو تشون دونغ ليو جينغ هونغ جون لو لينغ توان قانغ هونغ دونغ بن يو بينغ قانغ تشيو ليانغ جون تشيان فا شان كاي يو تشيو وي شو
Fengchao Nan Qin Dongzhu Qun Dong Liu Jing Hong Jun Lu Ling Tuan Gang Hong Dong Bin You Ping Wang Qiu Liang Jun Qian Fa Shan Kai Yue Qiu Wei Shuo Heng Wei Gang
Fengchao Nan Qin Dongzhu Qun Dong Liu Jing Hong Jun Lu Ling Tuan Gang Hong Dong Bin You Ping Wang Qiu Liang Jun Qian Fa Shan Kai Yue Qiu Wei Shuo Heng Wei Gang
Dongzhu Qun Dong Liu Jing Hong Jun Lu Ling Tuan Gang Hong Dong Bin You Ping Gang Qiu Liang Jun Qian Fa Shan Kai Yue Qiu Wei Shuo Heng Wei Gang Feng Xia Dong Guan
Dongzhu Qun Dong Liu Jing Hong Jun Lu Ling Tuan Gang Hong Dong Bin You Ping Gang Qiu Liang Jun Qian Fa Shan Kai Yue Qiu Wei Shuo Heng Wei Gang Feng Xia Dong Guan
Liu Jing Hong Jun Lu Ling Tuan Gang Hong Dong Bin You Ping Gang Qiu Liang Jun Han Fa Shan Kai Yue Qiu Wei Shuo Heng Wei Gang Feng Xia Dong Guan Long Zong Lin Sheng
ليو جينغ هونغ جون لو لينغ توان قانغ هونغ دونغ بن يو بينغ قانغ تشيو ليانغ جون هان فا شان كاي يو تشيو وي شو هنغ وي قانغ فنغ شيا دونغ غوان لونغ زونغ لين شنغ
Ping Gang Qiu Liang Jun Qian Fa Shan Kai Yue Qiu Wei Shuo Heng Wei Gang Feng Xia Dong Guan Long Wan Lin Sheng Meng Xin Lu Long Gang Chun Ni Tian Ying Jing Long Xue
بينغ قانغ تشيو ليانغ جون تشيان فا شان كاي يو تشيو وي شو هنغ وي قانغ فنغ شيا دونغ غوان لونغ وان لين شنغ منغ شين لو لونغ قانغ تشون ني تيان ينغ جينغ لونغ شيويه
Shan Kai Yue Qiu Wei Shuo Heng Wei Gang Feng Xia Dong Guan Long Wan Lin Sheng Meng Xin Lu Long Gang Chun Ni Tian Ying Jing Long Xue Jing Jun Fei Chao Hui Dong Le
شان كاي يو تشيو وي شو هنغ وي قانغ فنغ شيا دونغ غوان لونغ وان لين شنغ منغ شين لو لونغ قانغ تشون ني تيان ينغ جينغ لونغ شيويه جينغ يونيو فاي تشاو هوي دونغ لو
Gang Feng Xia Dong Guan Long Wan Lin Sheng Meng Xin Lu Long Gang Chun Ni Tian Ying Jing Long Xue Jing Suan Fei Chao Hui Dong Le Yan Qu Rui Long Tuo Bo Nan Gong Mo
عصابة فنغ شيا دونغ غوان لونغ وان لين شنغ منغ شين لو لونغ جانج تشون ني تيان ينغ جينغ لونغ شيويه جينغ سوان فاي تشاو هوي دونغ لو يان تشو روي لونغ تو بو نان قونغ مو
Lin Sheng Meng Xin Lu Long Gang Chun Ni Tian Ying Jing Long Xue Jing Jun Fei Chao Hui Dong Le Yan Han Rui Long Tuo Bo Nan Fan Mo Hao Kun
لين شنغ منغ شين لو لونغ قانغ تشون ني تيان ينغ جينغ لونغ شيويه جينغ يونيو فاي تشاو هوي دونغ لو يان هان روي لونغ توه بو نان فان مو هاو كون